Marco Di Summa

London, SE3

Email: mdisumma@yahoo.co.uk

Mobile: 07751841415

Website: marcodisumma.com

Passionate about art and technology and driven by new working aspirations, I committed the last four years to turn my interest into a career, building the foundation required to start my journey in the web industry and advance my technical skills within a professional setting.

Recently graduated in web development and looking for a junior position as a front-end developer, my expertise covers graphic design principles, digital media production and web development using the javascript framework and the MERN stack.

PROJECTS

Food Delivery Application 2022

- > Developed a full stack web application using MongoDB, Express.JS, React.JS, Node.JS.
- > Built layouts for a responsive user interface to allow visitors from any device.
- > Created the company logo and the graphic assets to enhance brand recognition
- Learned ES6 features as conditional ternary operator and short short-circuit evaluation.
- Implemented form validation, data manipulation and data retention.
- > Implemented the API endpoints supporting data type recognition and error handling.

Tower Defence Indie Game 2021

- > Developed user interfaces with the modern javascript frameworks, HTML, and CSS3.
- > Developed the brand identity and a marketing strategy for an indie company.
- > Design graphics assets, game characters and the storytelling to enhance users engagement
- > Learned image optimization, SVG graphic, for optimising web performance.
- > Applied SEO principles, user analytics, email and social media campaigns.

EDUCATION

2020 - 2022	Bachelor of Science in Web Development,	SAE Institute, London
2018 - 2020	Diploma in Graphic Design,	WAES Westminster, London
2019 - 2020	Award in Creative Media,	WAES Westminster, London
1993 - 1998	Diploma in Fine Art & Design	Liceo Artistico Ripetta, Rome

CODING SKILLS

➤ HTML5	> JSON	➤ Node
> CSS3	Javascript	MongoDb
> Sass	> React	> SVG

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite	➢ Git/GitHub	Visual Studio Code
Illustrator	InDesign	Postman
Photoshop	➤ Xd	Office Suit

ACADEMIC SKILLS

Colour Theory	Brand Principles	Back-end development
Typography	Logo Creation	Database
Layout Design	Infographic	REST Api
Media Production	Web Essential	Animation
Image Manipulation	Interactive Design	➤ SEO
Vector Graphic	Front-end Development	Media Communication

VOLUNTEER

2019 - 2020	Graphic Design Department	WAES Westminster, London
-------------	---------------------------	--------------------------

WORKING EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2018	Private Chef	London, UK
2014 - 2015	Cocomaya	London, UK
2012 - 2014	Tentazioni Restaurant	London, UK
1998 - 2012	Taverna Di Bacco	Rome, Italy

TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

20 years experience as a professional chef starting as owner of the family restaurant and then for a variety of establishments including Michelin starred and private clients:

- > Working under pressure and problem-solving to meet tight schedules;
- > Customer focus and attention to detail to deliver consistently high-quality service;
- > Time management and the ability to multitask in a demanding fast paced environment;
- > Leadership skills in managing kitchen staff and team dynamics;
- Creativity and adaptability in continuously evolving circumstances;
- > Understanding and implementation of budgeting and business management.

Reference upon request.